《黑镜》
《人与武器的对抗》
好了 家伙们 起床 起床 司特普
Okay, my people! Rise and shine. Get up, Stripe.
嘿 睡醒了吗
Hey. You awake yet?
- 清醒得一逼 - 步兵连
- Sure as shit ain't dreaming no more. - Company!
昨天 位于东边三英里的“情人瀑布”村
Something went down last night in Her Falls,
发生了状况
a village about three miles east.
我们接到报告 有座粮仓被闯入 洗劫一空
We've got reports of a food store broken into, shit stolen.
当地人认为是蟑螂干的
Locals think it's roaches.
蟑螂
Roaches!
我们五分钟后即将出发 走
We head out in five minutes. Let's go!
嘿 看上去你是第一次执行现实的蟑螂剿灭任务 哈
Hey, so, it looks like you're getting your first real-live roach hunt, huh?
嘿 新来的
Hey, new!
新来的
New!
我叫司特普
It's Stripe.
在你今天第一次直面蟑螂之前
Here's a little tip just in case you get your first toe-to-toe.
- 给你一点小建议 - 哈
- with one of them roaches today. - Uh-huh?
当你看到一只出现在面前的时候
When you see one right here,
不要吓得屁滚尿流 那只会激怒它们
try not to shit your pants. It's only gonna piss them off.
- 我尽量 - 尽量无视伦恩
- I'll try. - Try to ignore Len.
他的射击太烂 他是这世上唯一一个
His aim's so bad, he's the only guy on Earth.
吓到尿裤子还打不中的人
who could shit his own pants and miss.
- 去你的 村姑 - 村姑
- Fuck you, farm girl. - Farm girl?
是的 狩猎融入了我的血液
Yeah. Hunting's in my blood.
有人是有天赋的
Some of us are naturals.
出发
Moving out!
噢 是的
Whoo! Yeah!
喂喂喂 好了
Whoa, whoa, whoa. Okay.
你现在可以说话了
You can speak now.
- 这一定是蟑螂干的 - 蟑螂 你亲眼所见吗
- It must have been roaches. - Roaches, you see them? You see?
我没有亲眼看到
I didn't see them.
我听说过它们 一塌糊涂 一定是它们干的
I heard them. All the mess. It must have been them.
来块曲奇吗
Want a cookie?
- 好吧 - 它们在食物里待过
- Here you go. - They've been in the food.
我们会摧毁它们吃剩的东西
We'll have to destroy everything they left.
那些没人会吃的
No one will eat it.
我们可以更换它们 好吗
We can replace that, okay?
它们摧毁了冰箱 把它摧毁了还拿走了零件
They destroyed the cooler. Broke it and took the parts.
冰箱 它们偷了冰箱的零件
The cooler? They stole parts from the cooler?
它们往哪边跑了
Which way did they go?
它们在地上留下的脚印指出了方向
There were footprints in the dirt leading that way.
潘·海德卡
Parn Heidekker.
潘·海德卡 是个人名吗
Heidekker? Is that a name?
别让它们再来了 拜托 你必须阻止它们
Stop them coming. Please, you must stop.
好的
Okay.
我的孩子被吓坏了
I have child who is scared.
我会的 我保证
I will. I promise.
司特普
Stripe!
好了 这里的朋友认为蟑螂
Okay. Our friend here thinks that the roaches.
往一个叫潘·海德卡的家里去了
went in the direction of Parn Heidekker's place.
他是个怪人 听上去像是个宗教怪人
Local oddball, seems to be some kind of religious freak.
安德森 海格 我需要你们留在这里帮助他们把食物烧毁
Anderson, Hague, I want you to stay here and help them torch the food,
安抚他们的情绪
keep them calm and reassured.
剩下的人 我们去探访海德卡家
The rest of you, we're gonna drop in on Heidekker.
问些问题 搜查一下
Ask some questions, sniff around the place.
如果看到蟑螂 我们要展示出有备而来 出发
If there's roaches, we show we're ready for them. Let's go.
海德卡先生似乎并不是所谓的社交名流
So Mr. Heidekker is not exactly what you call a socialite or a mingler.
听上去他似乎有精神疾病
Seems like mental health issues.
据说他对于蟑螂他持有与众不同的观点
He's got some interesting views on roaches, by all accounts.
我把他的信息植入你们的主屏罩系统
I'm putting his info in your Mass system now.
几个月前就有关于他的投诉
Been complaints lodged against him going months back.
当地人声称他让蟑螂肆意出没在他的地盘 并且留食物给它们
Locals claim that he let roaches cross his land, left food out for them.
不过也许只是乡民的流言蜚语
Could be just shit talk from the local villagers though so…
还有多少蟑螂在外流窜
Yo, how many roaches we got left out here?
几千只 几百只
A couple of thousand? A couple of hundred, if that?
我想说 过去有几百万只
I mean, back home we had millions, man.
它们只用了两年时间就恢复到现在的数量
It only took two years to get shit back on track.
外面有乡巴佬丢东西给它们吃
Out here you got rustic fucks throwing them scraps.
难怪我们为什么要花那么多时间来善后了
No wonder it's taken so long to mop shit up.
不过为什么会有人蠢得要去帮助该死的蟑螂
But how can anyone be dumb enough to help a fucking roach?
是啊
Hell, yeah.
房子有前门
Portals front and rear.
没开灯
Windows blacked out.
烟囱在冒烟 有人在家
Chimney smoke. Someone's home.
伦纳德 你用炸弹
Lennard, you use the boomer.
好的 屏罩系统确认 每个人都看到全景图了吗
Okay, Mass check. Everyone got the layout?
- 确认 - 确认
- Check. - Check.
确认
Check.
艾金 凡尔肯 寇奇 你们搜查外围建筑
Aikin, Valcon, Coach, you check the outbuildings here.
一间一间慢慢搜
Take them one at a time and slow.
司特普 莱曼 你们跟着我和伦纳德
Stripe, Raiman, you come with me and Lennard.
我们去这里
We go in here.
伦纳德和我会和海德卡谈话 你们去搜剩下的房子
Len and I will talk to Heidekker, you check the rest of the house.
好的
Okay.
最好的结果是一枪不发
Optimal outcome, no shots fired.
做好面对蟑螂的准备
Except on a roach.
早上好先生
Morning, sir.
不需要翻译 我会你们的语言
There's no need for this. I speak your language.
好吧
Okay.
- 你想要什么 - 只是谈谈
- What is it you want? - Just to talk.
我们已经在谈了
That's what we're doing.
能好心地让我们进去谈谈吗
Be a little more neighbourly if we did it inside.
搜索二楼的房间
Check the upstairs rooms.
放松 我不是你的敌人
Relax. I'm not your enemy.
它们在哪里
Where are they?
谁
Where are who?
你知道的 我们在那座村庄里
You know, we got a whole bunch.
有一群害怕又生气的民众
of frightened, angry people in that village.
蟑螂们闯入了粮仓 偷走了供给
Roaches have been breaking into the food stores, stealing supplies.
你知道些什么吗
You know anything about that?
不知道
No.
不仅仅是它们偷走的食物
See, it's not just what they stole.
剩下的所有食物都会被销毁
All that food left is gonna be destroyed.
这样让大家的日子更难过了
Makes life harder for everyone.
穿过那边的围墙 你有你的准则
Cross on the wall there. You got principles.
你认为所有的生命都是神圣的 这我理解
Think all life is sacred. And I get it.
我同意 所有的生命都是神圣的 所以
I agree. All life is sacred so…
你甚至开始保护蟑螂 对吗
you even got to protect the roaches. Right?
他们的行为并不是他们的错 这一切不是他们想要的
It's not their fault they're like that. They didn't ask for this.
我懂 我们都懂
I get it. We get it.
嗯呢
Mm-hmm.
他们血液里的东西使他们变成了这样
There's shit in their blood that made them that way.
他们携带的病毒
The sickness they're carrying.
这不关乎生命是否神圣
That doesn't care about the sanctity of life.
或者是其他人是否要承受病痛的问题
or the pain about who else is gonna suffer.
如果我们不在五年 十年 二十年内阻止蟑螂
We don't stop the roaches, in five, ten, 20 years from now,
仍然会有孩子生出来就变成那样 然后它们会繁殖
you're still gonna get kids born that way, and then they're gonna breed.
这里
Bingo.
痛苦的轮回继续下去
And so it goes on. That cycle of pain.
而这些疾病本可以被避免
That sickness, and it could have been avoided.
蟑螂窝
Fucking roach nest.
我检查这里 我去检查楼梯
You check in there. I'll take the stairs.
你今天保护的每只蟑螂
Every roach you save today,
天知道明天会给多少人带去痛苦和绝望
you condemn God knows how many people to despair and misery tomorrow.
你不能还将它们视为人类
You can't still see them as human.
确实 你的情感值得被理解 但这是在误导
Understandable sentiment, granted, but it's misguided.
如果人类想继续生存 我们就得消灭他们
We gotta take them out if humankind is gonna carry on in this world.
真相就是这么残酷
That's just the hard truth.
总要有牺牲
Gotta make sacrifices.
什么鬼
What the fuck?
让我出去
Help me out here!
见鬼
Fuck!
莱
Rai!
我们要听这个圣父一直叨叨回基地吗
We gotta listen to Mr. Sunday School all the way back to base?
你能捂住耳朵
You can cover your ears.
好吧 又或者 我能让他永远说不出话来
Yeah, or, uh…I'll just hit permanent mute.
放下你的武器
Lower your weapon.
蟑螂爱好者也能杀的 对吧
Roach lover counts as a kill too, right?
他是个平民 对吧
He's a civ, right?
要是你向平民开枪了 那你这辈子都得背负这件事了
You shoot a civ, that's gonna stay with you the rest of your life.
哟 司特普 你怎么这么认真呢
Yo, Stripe, why don't you, uh…pull the stick out of your ass?
我只是逗他玩的 又不是逗你
Because I'm fucking with him, not you.
但是我猜你们两个都被我骗到了 对吧
I guess I had you both going, right?
好了
All right!
烧掉这个地方
Let's torch the place.
嘿 你还好吗 伙计
Hey, you okay, man?
没事
Yeah.
- 我听说你刚刚杀了一只蟑螂 - 两只
- I heard you popped one in there. - Two.
等等 两只
Wait, two?
- 我又杀了一只 用我的刀杀的 - 用刀杀的 天了噜
- I got another one, with my knife. - With your knife? Holy shit!
- 挺厉害的 是吧 - 是了 你这个该死的终结者
- Pretty good, right? - Yeah, you fucking Terminator.
日了 第一次出任务 他杀了俩
Damn! First time out, he gets two.
你这个幸运的混蛋 伙计
You lucky motherfucker, man.
祝你这个混蛋今夜好梦
Sweet dreams for this asshole.
今晚能尝到甜头了
Gonna get a treat tonight.
我爱你
I love you.
哇 射得好小姐
Whoa! Miss Sharp Shooter.
丢人的家伙
Patronising fuck!
冷酷无情 你这个死神
Ruthless! You're the Grim Reaper.
是啊 下一次没有蟑螂能逃脱
Yeah, well, no roach gets away next time.
你是不是还在在意那事
Are you still sweating that?
我从小就开始追捕鹿了 从不放弃
Well, I grew up tracking deer.You never give up.
我不喜欢让它们跑掉
I don't like it when they get away.
挺好的
Nice.
要是那些混蛋跑到森林里去
Yeah, if that fucker made it to the forest,
也许就能跑到边境那边 永远消失了
probably made it to the border, gone for good.
对你来说是没什么
Yeah. It's all right for you.
你杀了两只
You popped two of 'em.
但是我已经很久没杀到蟑螂了
It's been a while for me.
你懂的 我已经饥渴难耐了
You know, the gal is getting twitchy.
别这样 莱
Come on, Rai.
你睡得还好吗
You sleep good?
我睡得还行
Yeah, I slept OK.
什么 你就打算跟我说这个
What, that's all you're gonna give me?
真的吗 你知道吗 要是我一次杀了两只
Okay? You know, if I got two in one go,
我可能会高潮一个小时
I would want to come for like an hour!
好了 闭嘴
All right, shut up.
好吧
All right.
就是这样
Ah! That's the way.
嘿 你还好吗 伙计
Hey, you okay, man?
没事 我觉得我累了 就这样
Yeah, think I'm tired is all.
好吧 看来你昨晚的确过得挺好的
All right, so you did have a good night.
39 40 41
39, 40, 41…
42…
43 44 43 46
43, 44, 45, 46,
47 48 49
47, 48, 49,
50 51 52
50, 51, 52,
53 54 55
53, 54, 55,
56 57 58 59
56, 57, 58, 59…
强壮与纯洁
Strong and pure.
- 嘿 司特普 你还好吗 - 没事
- Hey, Stripe, you okay? - Yeah.
我是说 我 我不知道
I mean, I… don't know.
我感觉有点不对劲
I feel a little off.
我是说 我并没有生病什么的 只是
I mean, I ain't sick or nothing. It's just, uh…
去医务室报道
Report to the sick bay.
诊断中
Running diagnostic.
你看到了什么
What do you see?
一个立方体
A cube.
- 正在旋转中吗 - 是的
- Rotating? - Yeah.
- 现在呢 - 一棵树
- And now? - A tree.
- 像是苹果树 - 点击树上的苹果
- Like an apple tree. - Touch the apples for me.
满分
Full marks.
- 你说你头疼吗 - 是的 但是只是很快一阵
- So you say you had like a headache? - Yeah, but just quick.
没什么大不了的 只是
Nothing big, just…
看上去你一切无恙啊
Well, everything looks okay.
没有任何故障的迹象 你的植入体也没有任何问题
No sign of any malfunction or dropout with your Mass implant.
然后身体上 你好得不得了
And physically, you're in exemplary shape.
你刚刚经历过实战 你应该要预料到你会有点副作用
You've just seen combat, you can expect some sort of side effect.
有那么个 个东西
There was this, uh… this thing…
在农舍里 有光
with a light on it at the farmhouse.
- 蟑螂手里的 - 蟑螂的东西吗
- Roach had it. - A roach had it?
- 有点像手电筒 - 手电筒
- Kind of like a flashlight. - Flashlight?
有点像
Kinda.
我不知道
I don't know.
认真的 你没事 你的植入物没事 你的血液检测没事 一切都没事
Seriously, you're fine. Your Mass is fine. Blood's fine. It's all fine.
好吧
Okay. Yeah.
也许你该和奎特谈一谈
Maybe you should speak to Arquette.
谁是奎特
Who's Arquette?
所以 你就是库南切吗
So, you must be Koinanchey?
库南格 他们叫我司特普
Koinange. Folks call me Stripe.
为什么他们会这样叫你
Why would they call you that?
我猜他们也不能读出库南格的音吧
Couldn't pronounce Koinange either, I guess.
- 那挺好笑的 - 谢谢
- That's funny. - Thank you.
稍息 孩子 坐下吧
At ease, son. Sit down.
所以你最近实施了你第一次杀戮
So you recently logged your first kills?
- 两只蟑螂 - 嗯嗯
- Two roaches? - Uh-huh.
第一次出任务 可真不容小觑
First time out. It's impressive.
我猜是吧
Yeah, I guess.
发生了什么
So what happened?
- 什么 杀蟑螂吗 - 嗯嗯
- What, with the kills? - Mm-hmm.
噢 我当时在一个农舍
Oh. I'm in this, uh… farmhouse.
那里有个 像是密室这样的东西
There's this, like, hidden room or something.
我们走进去然后他们就在那里
We go in and there they are.
第一个 我就 是本能反应吧 直接开枪了 你懂吗
First one, I just… It was automatic. Just pop-pop, you know?
对 就像训练里的一样
Right. Just like in training.
对 就是那样 嗯
Yeah, just like that, yeah. Yeah.
- 然后第二个呢 - 他当时和我一起在地上
- And the second? - I mean, he was on the ground with me.
他吗
He?
那是个公的
It was a he.
噢
Oh.
所以那算是近距离交锋了吧
So, this was close quarters then?
对 他压在我身上 挣扎着
Yeah, he's on top of me. Struggling, I mean…
我拿不到我的枪 所以我只能用刺他
I couldn't reach my rifle so I had to stick him.
是刺它 用我的刀
Stick it. With my knife.
然后那让你是什么感受呢
And how did that… feel?
- 什么 像是怎么 - 情感上是什么感受
- What, like…? - Emotionally.
我没什么感觉 我是说 太快了 那是自卫
I didn't. I mean, it was quick. It was self-protection.
我猜我能感觉到的只有 松了一口气
I guess all I felt was, you know, relief.
- 只有松了一口气吗 - 嗯嗯
- Just relief? - Uh-huh.
不过对你来说没有别的感觉也并不算少见
It's not unusual to experience other feelings too.
甚至会有一瞬间的兴奋
A moment of euphoria even.
我猜是吧
Yeah, I guess.
我不知道 我觉得也许我会
I don't know, I thought maybe I'd feel…
我不知道
I don't know.
- 别的什么感觉吗 - 对 就像
- Something else? - Yeah, like…
后悔 这样的感觉 但是就是没有
Regret. Something like that, but that just wasn't there.
所以再给你一次机会你还是会那样做吗
So you'd do it again?
当然
Yeah, sure.
所以 你为什么会在这里
So… why are you here?
我不知道 我是说
I don't know. I mean…
我有过奇怪的感觉
I had a few weird moments.
我的屏罩系统看起来好像有故障
My Mass looked like it was glitching out.
但是你的植入物 我是说 它们通过了每项诊断
But your implants, I mean, they passed every diagnostic.
- 没有任何问题吗 - 是啊 他们说没有问题
- There is nothing wrong with that? - Yeah, they said it's fine.
我不知道 我觉得我只是
I don't know, I think I just…
感觉有点什么不对劲吧
Felt like something was up with it.
- 但是没有什么不对劲的地方 - 对
- But there's not. - No.
你做了件大事 你该为自己感到骄傲
You did a big thing. You should be proud of yourself.
好吗
Okay?
会过去的
It'll pass.
今晚让你好好睡一觉 好吗
Let's get you a good sleep tonight, huh?
真正的酣眠
A real good sleep.
干我
Fuck me.
差得远呢
Way to go, fuck fingers.
似乎我们对海德卡进行审问之后他并没有沉默多久
It seems Heidekker didn't stay silent too long once we got to work on him.
他交待了一个地点 蟑螂们曾经在那里觅食
He's given up a location, someplace the roaches have been scavenging.
嗯 好的
Well, all right.
那是间从战争开始之后就闲置的房子
It's a housing project that's been empty since the war.
离这里不远
It's not far from here.
控制台希望我们在回基地之前去侦查一下
So control wants us to do recon before we go back to base.
我们能快点吗
Can we hurry it up here?
我们应该烧毁整个森林的 是吧
We ought to burn the whole forest down, huh?
让那些蟑螂无处可逃
Give those roaches nowhere to run.
好的 你看见那处了吗
Okay, you see that?
太阳能电池板看着比其他的干净
Solar panel looks cleaner than the rest.
还有些电缆
And there are some cables.
- 肯定是蟑螂们在获取电能呢 - 为什么是这里
- There's got to be roaches leaching power. - Why here?
上帝才知道
Christ knows.
好吧
All right.
最好打电话问问
Better dial it in.
控制台 我是梅迪纳
Control. This is Medina.
有效账号 在这间房子附近发现了生物活动迹象
Positive ID. Signs of activity here at the housing project location.
看见了一块太阳能电池板 看着最近被擦干净过 还有一些电缆
Sighted one solar panel, looks recently wiped clean and some cabling.
明白
Roger so far.
- 你那边还好吗 - 闻闻草地
- You all right there? - Smell the grass.
我们一般什么也闻不到
We can't usually smell nothing.
- 你曾经注意过吗 - 没有 我从没注意过
- You ever noticed that? - No, I never noticed that.
请求行动方案
Requesting course of action.
未能读取 请重复
Didn't read. Please repeat.
好的
Okay.
控制台说我们应该后退 并且等待
Control says we should fall back and await comm…
妈的
Shit!
梅迪纳
Medina.
噢
Oh!
梅迪纳
Medina.
司特普 退后 她死了 快
Stripe, get back! She's dead. Come on!
好的 准备好了吗 掩护我
Okay. Ready? Cover me.
拉伊 拉伊 快
Rai! Rai, come on.
好
Okay.
哦 该死的蟑螂搞了柄来复枪 天啊
Oh, fucking roach got a rifle. Jesus Christ.
草 他妈的
Fuck. Piece of shit.
好的 司特普
Okay, Stripe.
司特普 快 聚在一起 哥们
Stripe, come on. Get it together, dude.
他开了六枪 他的来复枪看起来是老式的手动枪机
He fired six shots. His rifle looks old, bolt action.
- 上膛需要十秒钟 - 我们进去吗
- Should take him ten seconds to reload. - We go in?
我们进去 然后把他弄出来 你跟我一起吗
We go in and take him out. Are you with me?
- 我跟你一起 - 走吧
- I'm with you. - Let's go!
跟着我
Follow me!
准备好了吗 好的 三 二 一 掩护我
Ready? Okay, three, two, one. Cover me.
快啊 哥们 什么玩意
Come on, man! What the fuck?
这他妈是什么
What the fuck is this shit?
走
Let's go.
司特普
Stripe!
喔 喔 没事的 嘿 嘿
Whoa, whoa! It's okay. Hey. Hey.
冷静 冷静 冷静
Calm down. Calm down. Calm down.
没事的 没事 我不会伤害你的
It's okay. It's okay. I'm not gonna hurt you.
我不会伤害你 好吗
I'm not gonna hurt you. Okay?
继续 从这里出去 继续
Go on, get out of here. Go on.
这里不安全 有蟑螂在这儿
It's not safe. There's roaches here.
继续 拿
Go on. Get.
快
Come on!
- 莱 你干了什么 - 闭嘴 快
- Rai, what did you do? - Shut up! Come on!
你干了什么 莱
What did you do, Rai?
找到你们了
Got ya.
莱
Rai!
不要
No!
- 跑 - 你他妈干什么呢啊
- Run! - What the fuck are you doing?
- 你在杀他们 - 他们是蟑螂
- You're killing them! - They're roaches!
你他么正在杀他们呢 莱 去你的
You're fucking killing them, Rai! Fuck you!
你脑子出什么问题了 哥们 进屎了吧
What the fuck's wrong with you, man? You got some blown shit.
- 齐心协力啊 - 不要
- Pull it together! - No.
你还好吗
Are you all right?
你得离开这里 快
You gotta get out of here. Come on.
快点
Come on!
操
Fuck!
你最好跑快点儿
You better run.
嘘 嘘
Shh. Shh.
这里
Here.
我没事
I'm all right.
你能看到我本来的样子
You see me as I am.
我当然能看见你
Of course I see you.
你没有看见蟑螂吗
You don't see roach?
你不是蟑螂
You ain't a roach.
蟑螂全都是
Roaches is all…
乱七八糟的吗
Fucked up?
蟑螂不会说话
Roaches don't speak.
你只是听不到我们说话
You just can't hear us.
- 你他妈说什么呢 - 你的植入物 你的军用植入物
- What the fuck are you talking about? - Your implants. Your army implants.
屏罩系统
The Mass system?
他们把它放入你的脑中 帮助你战斗
They put it in your head to help you fight,
当它发挥作用时 你会把我们看成别的东西
and when it works, you see us as something other.
我们之中的一个 卢卡 之前在做一种 一种机器
One of us, Luka, was making a… a machine.
光线 据说它可以干扰植入物
Light flashes. Said it can interfere with the implant.
你是蟑螂吗
You're roaches?
但是我见过蟑螂
But I've seen roaches.
我见过他们 他们都他妈的 像是
I've seen them, they're fucking… They're like, uh…
- 动物吗 - 不是 他们是怪兽 我见过他们
- Animals? - No, they're monsters. I've seen them.
植入物让你看到的
The implant made you see this.
操 那些村民 呢
Fuck. The villagers… Huh?
土著们 他们 他们不是军人 他们脑子里没有集体屏罩系统
The locals, they… they ain't army. They got no Mass in their heads.
他们害怕蟑螂
They're scared of the roaches.
- 他们恨这东西 - 每个人都恨我们
- They hate the fucking things. - Everybody hates us.
他们看见的是什么 啊
Well, what the fuck do they see? Huh?
那些该死的市民们 当他们看见蟑螂的时候 他们看见的是什么
The fucking civs, when they look at a roach, what do they see?
和你现在见到的一样
What you see now.
他们还是恨 因为他们就是这样被教导的
They hate all the same because it's what they've been told.
十年前 开始的
Ten years ago, it began.
战后
Post-war.
首先 筛查计划 检查DNA
First, the screening programme, the DNA checks,
接着登记 紧急措施
then the register, the emergency measures.
而很快 每个人开始管我们叫怪物 肮脏的怪物
And soon everyone calls us creatures. Filthy creatures.
每种声音 电视 电脑
Every voice. The TV. The computer.
说我们有 我们体内有疾病
Say we have… we have sickness in us.
我们有弱点 在我们的血液里
We have weakness. It's in our blood.
他们说我们的血液不能传承下去
They say that our blood cannot go on.
所以我们不能存活下去
That we cannot go on.
我的名字曾是卡塔里娜
My name was Catarina.
他的曾是亚历克
He was Alec.
现在我们只是蟑螂
Now we're just roach.
但是现在
But now…
现在你看到我了
Now you see me.
莱
Rai?
莱 不要
Rai, no!
告诉我我不该杀你
Tell me I shouldn't kill you.
- 一切都不是真的 莱 - 你中什么邪了
- None of it's true, Rai. - What the fuck got you?
一切都不是真的
None of it's true.
去你的吧
Fuck you.
起来 背对着墙
Get up. Back against the wall.
起来
Get up!
你想让我进到里面去吗
You want me to come in there?
没事的 我跟他聊聊就好
It's all right. I can just talk to him.
谢谢你 布里利
Thank you, Briley.
司特普
Stripe.
我们欠你个道歉 我们没能在你的屏罩系统里发现错误
We owe you an apology. We didn't spot the fault in your Mass.
我给你带了杯咖啡
I got you a coffee.
你在农场发现的设备 和医生说的那个
The device you found in the farmhouse, you mentioned it to the doctor.
是这个东西吗
Is this the thing?
我们在你和莱搜查过的旧街区里找到的
We found it on an old block that you and Raiman were searching.
像是他们用我们的设备零件进行了反工程
Looks like they reverse engineered it from some of our drone parts and so on.
里面的光可以传送代码 就像病毒
The light here transmits a code. It's like a virus.
它会融入你的屏罩系统 并从内部关闭它
It burrows into your Mass, trying to shut it down from within.
跟你说 那些蟑螂变得比
I tell you, those roaches are getting more ingenious.
我们想象得聪明得多
than we give them credit for.
整件事就是一个骗局
The whole thing is a lie.
我明白你为什么那么说 真的
I understand why you'd say that, yeah.
蟑螂
Roaches.
他们看起来和我们一样
They look just like us.
的确一样
Of course they do.
这就是他们如此危险的原因
That's why they're so dangerous.
人类啊 你知道 我们不得不做这些坏事
Humans. You know, we give ourselves a bad rap,
但作为同一个物种却又真心地同情彼此
but we're genuinely empathetic as a species.
我是说 我们并不想互相杀戮
I mean, we don't actually really want to kill each other.
这是好事
Which is a good thing.
除非你的未来要建立在清除敌人的基础上
Until your future depends on wiping out the enemy.
来吧 坐下
Come on, sit down.
我不知道你在学校里学了多少历史
I don't know how much history you studied in school.
许多年前 我是说20世纪初
Many years ago, I'm talking early 20th century,
多数士兵甚至不开枪
most soldiers didn't even fire their weapons.
或者他们朝着敌人头顶放空枪
Or if they did, they would just aim over the heads of the enemies.
他们是故意的
They did it on purpose.
第一次世界大战中的英军
British Army. World War I.
他们的陆军准将随军出征时 会拿一根棍子
The brigadier, he'd walk the line with a stick.
用痛打手下的方法命令他们开枪
and he'd whack his men in order to get them to shoot.
即使是在第二次世界大战交火中
Even in World War II, in a firefight,
也只有15%到20%的人或扣下扳机
only 15%, 20% of the men would pull the trigger.
世界的命运到了紧急关头 但是也只有15%的人开枪
The fate of the world at stake and only 15% of them fired.
这些说明了什么
Now what does that tell you?
我认为这说明如果军方能力更全面
It tells me that that war would have been over a whole lot quicker.
战争可以尽快结束
had the military got its shit together.
所以改变开始了
So we adapted.
加强训练 提高反应能力
Better training. Better conditioning.
在后来的越战中
Then comes the Vietnam War,
开火的概率提升到了85%
and the shooting percentage goes up to 85.
子弹横飞 但是死伤率还是很低
Lot of bullets flying. The kills were still low.
那些击毙敌人的士兵
Plus the guys who did get a kill,
回来之后 大多数人的精神状态都出现了问题
well, most of them came back all messed up in the head.
直到屏罩系统出现 事情才有所改观
And that's pretty much how things stayed until Mass came along.
你看 屏罩系统 是终极的军事武器
You see, Mass… Well, that's the ultimate military weapon.
它可以改变你的大脑
It helps you with your intel.
目标命中率 通讯 反应能力
Your targeting. Your comms. Your conditioning.
向可怕的怪物开枪要容易得多 对吧
It's a lot easier to pull the trigger when you're aiming at the bogeyman, hmm?
不仅是你的眼睛 你的其它感官也被它管理
It's not just your eyes, though. Takes care of your other senses, too.
你听不到尖叫声
You don't hear the shrieks.
闻不到血腥和便溺
You don't smell the blood and the shit.
他们是人啊
They're human beings.
你知道他们的DNA里有多少恶心的东西吗
Do you have any idea the amount of shit that's in their DNA?
高患癌率
Higher rates of cancer.
肌肉萎缩症 多发性硬化症 SLS 智商低下
Muscular dystrophy. MS. SLS. Substandard IQ.
犯罪倾向 性异常
Criminal tendencies. Sexual deviances.
这些都有
It's all there.
这都是检查结果
The screening shows it.
你想下一代人是这样的吗
Is that what you want for the next generation?
别觉得你的工作很坏
Don't feel bad about doing your job.
村民们不会做
The villagers won't do it.
你的父母不会做
The folks back home won't do it.
因为他们没有屏罩系统
They don't have Mass.
屏罩系统帮你完成
Mass lets you do it.
你
You.
是在保护血统
You're protecting the bloodline.
而那 我的朋友 是个荣耀
And that, my friend, is an honour.
狗屁荣耀
There's no honour here.
那就是杀戮
It's just killing.
- 谎言和杀戮 - 没人跟你说谎
- Lying and killing. - No one lied to you.
你知道一切 自始至终
You knew all of this. All along.
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
是你自己同意植入屏罩系统的
You agreed to have your Mass implant put in.
并且激活 每个军人都这样做
Set up. Every soldier does.
我们不能强行植入并且给你制造一个幻象 你的大脑会抗拒的
We can't just embed it and feed you a dream. Your mind would reject it.
你必须接受 自愿地
You have to accept it. Willingly.
你就是这样做的
It's exactly what you did.
条款和条件你都看了吗
So you see the terms and conditions there?
是的 整个资料都看了
Yeah, that's like a whole essay, man.
那是什么
What is that?
这是你同意植入屏罩系统时的录像 你六个月前签字的时候录的
That's your consent video. From when you signed up six months ago.
基本上 里面的内容就是 你同意激活你的屏罩系统移植物
Basically, it says you agree to Mass implant activation.
- 我没做过这个 - 你做过
- I didn't do this. - Yes, you did.
- 功能就像是催眠 - 嗯 好
- Works kind of like hypnosis. - Yeah, all right.
你将不会想起
Part of what you're agreeing to is not realising.
被调来这个州
you've been put in this state.
接下来 你甚至会忘掉这次谈话
If you follow me. You won't recall this conversation.
听起来挺滑稽 哥们儿
That's kind of funny, man.
关上
Turn it off.
- 为了表示同意 - 关上
- So for you to register consent… - Turn it off, man.
你点那里录下指纹
I'm gonna need your thumbprint there.
- 这儿吗 - 是的
- Right here? - Yes, please.
很屌哦
That's dope.
那不是我
I didn't do that!
- 我不记得了 - 跟那个人说的一样
- I don't remember that! - Just like the man said.
- 我知道你不高兴 - 滚你的
- I know you're upset. - Fuck you!
- 怎么回事 - 我们可以控制你看到的东西 司特普
- What's happening? - We control what you see, Stripe.
- 我什么也看不见 - 因为我们控制了你的视力
- I can't see nothing. - Because we control it.
他妈的还我眼睛
Give me my fucking eyes back.
- 让我给你几个选择 - 他妈的还我眼睛
- Let me lay out your options. - Give me my fucking eyes back, man!
让我给你几个选择吧
Let me lay out your options!
选择一 你同意重置你的屏罩系统
Option one, you agree to have your Mass reset.
过去几天的记忆
All the recollections of the past few days,
包括今天的谈话都会被清除
including this conversation, erased.
没门
No way.
选择二 监禁
Option two's incarceration.
- 我建议你慎重考虑 - 滚你妈的
- I'd advise you to consider. - Fuck you!
屏罩系统是你的朋友
Mass is a friend.
如果没有它 你会记得所有你做过的事
Without it, you will remember everything that you did.
我不要这狗屁玩意儿
I ain't having this Mass shit.
不要 不要
No more. No way.
好
Okay.
那么
Well…
也许你该看看没有它 生活是什么样
Maybe you should see what life would be like without it.
怎么了
What's happening?
我在哪儿
Where am I?
海德卡牧场 三天前
Heidekker's ranch. Three days ago.
我们都记录下来了 司特普 我们可以让你看你做的所有事
I have it all logged, Stripe. We can feed you everything that you did.
嘿 不 不 不 不
Hey, no, no, no. No.
求你了 别开枪 别 求你了 别开枪
Please! Please don't shoot. Please! Please! Please don't shoot.
- 求你了 求你了 - 不 不
- Please! Please! - No! No!
不 停下
No. Make it stop.
不 求你了
No! Please.
停下
Make it stop!
求你了
Please!
不 不
No! No!
不
No!
我擦 停下来
Fuck off! Stop it!
不
No!
你可以看见 闻见 感觉到所有事物
You'll see and smell and feel it all.
这就是你想要的吗
Is this what you want?
反复循环 孤单地待在一个牢房里
On a loop? In a cell all alone?
我们可以抹去那段记忆
We can make that go away.
也抹去这次谈话
This conversation goes away too.
所有都抹去
All of it.
但你必须得说那个词
But you gotta say the word.
说出那个词 司特普
Just say the word, Stripe.
这样一切就会消失
And it all goes away.
说那个词
Just say the word.